Nicolas Hunter

nickthedev95@gmail.com ~ 305-206-5293 ~ https://nolimitsnick.com/ ~ https://github.com/nolimitsnick

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Computer Engineer with over two years of industry experience seeking to leverage strong software development skills with network and cloud computing knowledge in a DevOps / Cloud based role. Excellent reputation for resolving problems, automating workflows, and driving overall operational improvements. Knowledgeable in Amazon Web Services, Linux (CentOS, Debian), Scripting (Python, JS, Bash), Object Oriented Programming(Java), Network Security, Agile Methodologies, Git and Continuous Integration Continuous Deployment (CICD).

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science in Computer Engineering

December 9th, 2018

Florida International University (FIU); Miami, FL

Concentrations: Data System Software, Cybersecurity and Embedded Operating Systems

Kubernetes Hands-On - Deploy Microservices to the AWS Cloud

December 2019 - February 2020, Online

http://ude.my/UC-1b6b3334-a4f8-4d02-a6ec-c4211baceb4d

- Utilized KOPS, Helm package manager to deploy and manage a production grade Kubernetes cluster to Amazon Web Services complete with role-based access control, autoscaling, and high availability.
- Monitored cluster metrics and configured alerts to send directly to Slack channel through usage of EFK(Elasticsearch, Fluentd, Kibana) stack, Grafana, Prometheus and Alert Manager.
- Wrote infrastructure as code to implement Continuous Integration/ Continuous Deployment on the cluster by setting up an organizational pipeline via Jenkins server configurations.

CERTIFICATIONS

Amazon Web Services (AWS)

AWS Certified SysOps Administrator (Associate)

• Validation Number: ETJQMYFKH2V11ZKM

AWS Certified Solutions Architect (Associate)

• Validation Number: F5TKC6CK31F4QCW8

AWS Certified Developer (Associate)

Validation Number: 0Y0948EKGMFQ1J58

February 2020 – February 2023

August 2019 - August 2022

July 2019 - July 2022

KNOWLEDGE

Languages: Java, Javascript, Python, SQL, NoSQL, Bash/Batch, C++/C, JSON, YAML, XML

Amazon Web Services: EC2 (ALB + ASG), S3, VPC, Route53, CloudWatch, CLI, SQS, SNS, RDS, Serverless (Lambda, API Gateway, DynamoDB), CI/CD (CloudFormation, CodeBuild, CodeDeploy, CodePipeline, Jenkins), Security (IAM, Cognito, KMS, Secrets Manager, Parameter Store, CloudTrail)

Technologies : Elastic Beanstalk, Docker + Kubernetes (ECS, EKS, KOPS), NodeJS, Express, React, Jest, Mirth Connect, Git/SVN, HTTP Listeners, Elasticsearch, Fluentd, Kibana, Prometheus,

EXPERIENCE

Tellus LLC

January 2019 - Current

Integrations System Engineer

- Developed secure end-to-end client delivery pipeline using Java, JavaScript, MySQL, SMTP, Amazon Web Services (EC2, KMS, SFTP Gateway, S3, RDS)
- Built and maintained interfaces for ETL(Extract, Transform, Load) health care integrations using various messaging protocols and connection methods via Mirth Connect.
- Monitored and optimized fleet of EC2 instances using AWS best practices(CloudWatch, IAM, System Manager)
- Created technical and clearly understandable documentation for both internal and external audiences' that define processes, specifications and functionality of interfaces
- Collaborated in team-based, Agile environment to accomplish objectives in measured and open manner.

Bayview Asset Management

June 2018 – December 2018

Java Developer

- Developed robust Java code for Spring/Spring Boot applications.
- Utilized knowledge of SQL, SOAP and REST to supplement Java development
- Upgraded Spring Boot application monitoring admin server with role-based authorization filters backed by a LDAP Authentication database for monitoring company client application metrics under different staging environments
- Designed Java scheduled job process to consume API hosted on an SSL certified client web server and push specified payload to internal Microsoft SQL Server database

PROJECTS

Serverless Portfolio

August 2019 - Current

http://nickthedev.nolimitsnick.com

- Proof of concept CI/CD Pipeline created using Git, CodeBuild, CodeDeploy, CodePipeline, Lambda, CloudWatch and SNS to continuously push new updates to application.
- Secure and highly available dynamic website distributed via Route 53 and CloudFront.
- Built React.js portfolio web app using (JSX, ES6, Babel, Webpack, Chai/Mocha, Jest, Enzyme)
- Scripted SNS notification and portfolio deployment Lambda functions using Python 3.7, Pipenv and boto3.

Senior Design Project - RFID Logistics System

January 2018 - December 2018

- Worked with team of 5 to designed a cross platform RFID IoT middleware application for Linux based systems that supports Read/Write functionality of Generation 2 UHF RFID tags.
- Connected M6E Nano RFID Reader with Single Board Computer over USB serial to allow RFID tag data to be pushed to a NodeJS Web Service hosted on an AWS EC2 Instance,
- Integrated Python scripting and various Amazon Web Services technology stacks to utilize AWS Lambda(serverless) functions to interact with a Microsoft SQL Server database hosted on Amazon RDS.